<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/collections/all.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://robert-price.myshopify.com/collections/all"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://robert-price.myshopify.com/collections/giant-binoculars.atom"/>
  <title>Explore Scientific LLC</title>
  <updated>2021-01-26T13:55:34-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Explore Scientific LLC</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209316552876</id>
    <published>2021-01-26T13:55:34-06:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-26T13:55:34-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/u-mount-with-tripod-for-large-binoculars"/>
    <title>U-mount with tripod for large binoculars</title>
    <s:type>Mounts</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Explore Scientific</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0390/6029/products/4e01b10b80709b34ac09fb10fb8ad0e2_0114300_m_1.jpg?v=1611090231"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Explore Scientific<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Mounts<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            749.99
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="features">Features</h1>
<ul>
<li>Solid fork mount with tripod for large binoculars</li>
<li>Carries binoculars up to 12kg and a width of max.290mm</li>
<li>Soft and even movement of the large binoculars</li>
<li>Infinitely variable friction adjustment in both axes</li>
<li>Large handwheels - can also be operated with gloves</li>
<li>Adjustment range AZ / ALT: 360 degrees / 0 to 90 degrees</li>
<li>Optimal vibration damping thanks to the stainless steel tripod</li>
<li>Comfortable observation position in all positions</li>
<li>Adjustment height of tripod with mount: approx. 100 to 140 cm</li>
<li>Integrated accessory tray made of aluminum</li>
</ul>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="description">Description</h1>
<p>When using large binoculars, a stable mount and tripod with a suitable load-bearing capacity are essential. The new EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC U-mount with field tripod has been specially designed for the EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC BT large binoculars series, but also fits most other binoculars with a lens diameter of 70 to 120mm that have a 1/4 inch photo thread connection on the underside. With the U-mount there is no shaking or annoying vibrations, the combination is as if made from one piece and provides unadulterated observation fun in all setting positions of the binoculars. Regardless of whether you are surveying the starry sky or observing the landscape, the U-Mount is a solid base for your large binoculars and enables smooth and even movements in both axes.</p>
<p><strong>The U-mount as a base for large binoculars and always with you on every excursion </strong><br>An easily transportable but solid mount is essential when using large binoculars. A simple photo tripod with a ball head or video tilt head is quickly overwhelmed here. The new EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC U-mount has a fine-grained mechanism with adjustable friction in both axes, and enables easy adjustment and tracking even when the payload is fully utilized. Depending on the set intensity of the friction, the position of the binoculars is kept stable or a soft and even movement can take place. The large adjusting screws on both axes run smoothly and are easy to use even with gloves and clammy fingers. The massive construction of the U-mount reduces vibrations to an absolute minimum. Even at high magnification there is no blurring and the finest details can be observed. The U-mount and tripod can be separated for easy transport.</p>
<p><strong>Assembly of the large binoculars on the U-mount </strong><br>With the help of the quick-change adapter plate included in the scope of delivery, the binoculars can be mounted and removed again in a few seconds. This is a major advantage, especially for mobile outdoor use. The connection between the binoculars and the adapter plate is made using two 1/4 inch threaded bolts (standard photo tripod thread), which are guided variably in an elongated hole. Universal use with different binoculars is therefore possible. The double screw connection guarantees a very secure fit of the binoculars. The adapter plate itself is also attached to the U-mount with the help of two large clamping screws, which can also be easily operated with gloves. Nothing wobbles here and all controls are easy to use.</p>
<p><strong>The field tripod provides a secure stand </strong><br>Regardless of the surface, the EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC tripod offers a secure stand. The solid aluminum and stainless steel construction effectively suppress any kind of vibrations. The 50mm diameter stainless steel tripod legs and the aluminum tripod head plate are an ideal combination and offer maximum stability with a moderate transport weight of only 5.8kg. With the tripod legs put on and pushed in, the transport dimensions are only 80cm long. The accessory tray included in the scope of delivery also serves to brace the tripod legs towards the outside and thereby increase stability. By pulling out the tripod legs, the working height for the binoculars can be individually adjusted in a range from approx. 100 to 140cm.</p>
<!--end tab--><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="specs">Specs</h1>
<table>
<colgroup> <col> </colgroup>
<thead></thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Item Number</td>
<td>01-14300</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total length</td>
<td>1000 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total width</td>
<td>1000 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total height</td>
<td>1390 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total net weight</td>
<td>11300 g</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Housing material</td>
<td>Mgnesium</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="warranty">Warranty</h1>
<p>Limited Warranty is one year, which converts to the Explore STAR Transferable Extended Life of the Product Warranty when product is registered within 60 days of purchase. <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/apps/product-registration">Click Here</a> to register.</p>
<p><!--end tab--></p>
<p style="font-size: 16px;">CA Residents: <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/pages/prop65" target="_blank">Prop 65 WARNING(S)</a></p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>500-1000</s:tag>
    <s:tag>600-800</s:tag>
    <s:tag>binoculars</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Brand_ Explore Scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Astronomy</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Birding</s:tag>
    <s:tag>explore-scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>mounts</s:tag>
    <s:tag>over-500</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-default</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-disabled</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209316552876</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="USD">749.99</s:price>
      <s:sku>01-14300</s:sku>
      <s:grams>14100</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209331200172</id>
    <published>2021-01-26T13:55:31-06:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-26T13:55:31-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/bt-120-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces"/>
    <title>BT-120 SF Large Binoculars with 62 Degree LER Eyepieces</title>
    <s:type>Binoculars</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Explore Scientific</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0390/6029/products/2c434c58450323676f8cb215705793e7_0114230_m_1.jpg?v=1614378503"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Explore Scientific<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Binoculars<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            2349.99
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="features">Features</h1>
<ul>
<li>Powerful large binoculars with a 120 mm objective diameter</li>
<li>Observe the moon, the planets and bright deep sky objects in the night sky as well as terrestrial targets</li>
<li>Extremely robust binoculars, sealed and filled with nitrogen</li>
<li>Convenient 45-degree view and individual focusing</li>
<li>Carrying handle makes it easier to transport the binocular and ensures a secure hold during tripod assembly</li>
<li>Includes two premium waterproof Explore Scientific 62 degree 20mm LER eyepieces</li>
<li>Eyepiece holder 1.25 inch / 31.7mm, interchangeable eyepieces</li>
<li>Extendable dew caps minimize condensation on the lenses</li>
<li>Tripod connection: 2 x 1/4 inch and 1 x 3/8 inch photo thread</li>
<li>Optional accessories: <a style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, 'San Francisco', 'Segoe UI', Roboto, 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif; font-size: 1.4em;" href="https://explorescientificusa.com/products/u-mount-with-tripod-for-large-binoculars" target="_blank">Item 01-14300 U-mount with field tripod</a><br>
</li>
</ul>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="description">Description</h1>
<p><meta charset="utf-8"><b>Giant binocular for observing the starry sky, nature and landscape. </b><br><span>Observe the beauty of the starry sky at night and distant objects in nature during the day. Globular star clusters, glowing gas nebulae, the moon with its craters and even planets can be observed wonderfully on a clear night. But also all other distant things in nature and landscape, even ships and airplanes can be seen in detail. With the all-round binoculars of the EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC BT series, you can get up very close. Thanks to the large, light-gathering lenses and the professional coatings on all lens surfaces, these binoculars produce bright and brilliant images even at night and at twilight, providing a special viewing pleasure. The comfortable 45 degree viewing angle allows fatigue-free use even when the binoculars are tilted strongly.  </span><br><br><b>A large binocular can also be called a double refractor telescope </b><br><span>One complete lens telescope with the full light gathering power is available per eye. Experience a whole new dimension of observing. Objects are reproduced almost vividly in these binoculars and observing with both eyes is basically very relaxed. Last but not least, this comfortable way of observation increases the recognition of the finest details and effectively prevents rapid eye fatigue. </span><br><br><b>Extremely robust binoculars with magnesium housing, sealed and filled with nitrogen  </b><br><span>The BT series binoculars are designed for tough outdoor use. The IPX6 sealed and nitrogen-filled design effectively prevents fogging of the internal optics even under difficult weather conditions. The very light magnesium housing saves weight and makes it easy to handle. Two EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC 20mm eyepieces of the 62 degree LER series already included. EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC is an established manufacturer of extremely high-quality eyepieces in the astronomy scene. An optical system is only as good as its weakest component. Therefore we have decided to deliver these giant binoculars with a pair of quality eyepieces of the 62 degree LER series. With an apparent field of view of 62 degrees and a focal length of 20mm, the BT-120 binoculars produce a 33x magnification. Thus these wide angle eyepieces offer a very good overview (field of view 1,8 degree) at moderate magnification. The large interpupillary distance of these LER (long eye relief) eyepieces of 15mm and soft silicone eyecups, which can be turned inside out, also guarantee a comfortable and relaxed view. For astronomy, a flat and sharp image field is advantageous and offers a particularly impressive viewing experience even during the day. Due to the waterproof design and the argon filling, these eyepieces are absolutely durable and easy to clean. </span><br><br><b>Interchangeable eyepieces with 1.25 inch / 31.7mm plug-in diameter </b><br><span>Adjust the magnification and field of view to your individual needs and choose from a wide range of available eyepieces. All eyepiece types with a plug-in diameter of 1.25 inch / 31.7mm can be used with the binoculars of the BT series. Especially recommended are EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC eyepieces of the 62 and 82 degree series with focal lengths from 8 to 26mm (see item No. 02188xx and 02196xx). The magnification can be varied from 25x to 75x (focal length binoculars: focal length eyepiece = magnification). The eyepieces are held in the binoculars by a precise brass compression ring clamp and guarantee a tilt free position.  </span><br><br><b>Use of color and nebula filters for astronomical observations </b><br><span>Increase the contrast and visibility of objects and details by screwing the corresponding filters directly into the thread of the eyepiece sleeves. The use of color and nebula filters must of course always be done in pairs. Suitable are all EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC screw filters with 1.25inch / 31.7mm diameter (see item No. 03102xx)  </span><br><br><b>Comfortable 45 degree view and helical single focus </b><br><span>The 45-degree viewing angle allows a relaxed observation position even when the binoculars are tilted strongly. Also the individual interpupillary distance can be adjusted in a range from 54 to 76mm. With the fine helical individual focusing, precise focusing is achieved effortlessly. Extendable dew caps The integrated dew caps can be removed in high humidity and cold conditions. This avoids fogging of the outer objective lenses and effectively shields additional control light coming in from the side. </span><br><br><b>Integrated carrying handle </b><br><span>A metal carrying handle located at the center of gravity facilitates transport and ensures a secure hold during tripod assembly. </span><br><br><b>Suitable tripods and tripod connection<br></b>When using these large binoculars, a sturdy photo tripod with an appropriate load capacity is highly recommended. The connection is made via two 1/4 inch or one 3/8 inch threaded holes (standard photo tripod thread) in the tripod adapter of the binoculars. The ideal solution is to use the optional available EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC U-Mount with field tripod (item No. 01-14300). This is specially designed for the large binoculars of the BT series and carries these devices absolutely safely. The excellent mechanism with adjustable friction in both axes allows easy moving and tracking. The binocular position is kept stable depending on the adjusted friction intensity. Vibrations are reduced to a minimum by the massive construction of the U-Mount and the large stainless steel tripod. Even at high magnification there are no vibrations and the finest details can be observed.</p>
<!--end tab--><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="specs">Specs</h1>
<table>
<colgroup> <col> </colgroup>
<thead></thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Item Number</td>
<td>01-14230 </td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Optical design</td>
<td>Achromatic refractor Porro</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mirror / lens diameter</td>
<td>120 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Focal length</td>
<td>660 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Focal ratio</td>
<td>5.5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Apparent Facial field</td>
<td>62 degrees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Type of remuneration</td>
<td>Enhanced Multilayer Desposition (EMD)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Exit pupil min.</td>
<td>3.6 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Field of view</td>
<td>1.8 degrees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Waterproof</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Water resistance protection level</td>
<td>IPX6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Exit pupil distance</td>
<td>15 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total length</td>
<td>654 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total width</td>
<td>290 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total height</td>
<td>156 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total net weight</td>
<td>8300 g</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Housing material</td>
<td>Mgnesium</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><!--end tab--><!--start tab--></p>
<h1 id="features">Warranty</h1>
<p>Explore Scientific offers free collimation service for the Giant Binoculars for the lifetime of the product. The customer is responsible for shipping both ways. <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/apps/product-registration" target="_blank">Explore Scientific Giant Binoculars come with a 1-year warranty when registered within 60 days of purchase. </a></p>
<p>The Explore Alliance membership program offers Extended Care for all Explore Scientific products with a paid membership. For more information on the Explore Alliance <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/products/explore-alliance-membership" target="_blank">Click Here</a> </p>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="manual">Manual</h1>
<p><a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0390/6029/files/BT_SF_Large_Binoculars.pdf?v=1625680797">Download Manual Here</a></p>
<p><!--end tab--></p>
<p style="font-size: 16px;">CA Residents: <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/pages/prop65" target="_blank">Prop 65 WARNING(S)</a></p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>1.1Options:Objective Diameter*70mm~/products/bt-70-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.2Options:Objective Diameter*82mm~/products/bt-82-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.3Options:Objective Diameter*100mm~/products/bt-100-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.4Options:Objective Diameter*120mm~/products/bt-120-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>2000-3000</s:tag>
    <s:tag>2200-2400</s:tag>
    <s:tag>binoculars</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Brand_ Explore Scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Astronomy</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Birding</s:tag>
    <s:tag>explore-scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>over-500</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-default</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-disabled</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209331200172</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="USD">2349.99</s:price>
      <s:sku>01-14230</s:sku>
      <s:grams>8300</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209308524716</id>
    <published>2021-01-26T13:55:21-06:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-26T13:55:21-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/bt-100-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces"/>
    <title>BT-100 SF Large Binoculars with 62 Degree LER Eyepieces</title>
    <s:type>Binoculars</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Explore Scientific</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0390/6029/products/46b3b5ea6521d5064beed06cc8d5b1d5_0114220_m_1.jpg?v=1614378510"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Explore Scientific<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Binoculars<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            1999.99
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="features">Features</h1>
<ul>
<li>Powerful large binoculars with a 100 mm objective diameter</li>
<li>Observe the moon, the planets and bright deep sky objects in the night sky as well as terrestrial targets</li>
<li>Extremely robust binoculars, sealed and filled with nitrogen</li>
<li>Convenient 45-degree view and individual focusing</li>
<li><span data-mce-fragment="1">Carrying handle makes it easier to transport the binocular and ensures a secure hold during tripod assembly</span></li>
<li>Includes two premium waterproof Explore Scientific 62 degree 20mm LER eyepieces</li>
<li>Eyepiece holder 1.25 inch / 31.7mm, interchangeable eyepieces</li>
<li>Extendable dew caps minimize condensation on the lenses<br>
</li>
<li>Tripod connection: 2 x 1/4 inch and 1 x 3/8 inch photo thread</li>
<li>Optional accessories: <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/products/u-mount-with-tripod-for-large-binoculars" target="_blank">Item 01-14300 U-mount with field tripod</a>
</li>
</ul>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="description">Description</h1>
<p><meta charset="utf-8"><b>Giant binocular for observing the starry sky, nature and landscape. </b><br><span>Observe the beauty of the starry sky at night and distant objects in nature during the day. Globular star clusters, glowing gas nebulae, the moon with its craters and even planets can be observed wonderfully on a clear night. But also all other distant things in nature and landscape, even ships and airplanes can be seen in detail. With the all-round binoculars of the EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC BT series, you can get up very close. Thanks to the large, light-gathering lenses and the professional coatings on all lens surfaces, these binoculars produce bright and brilliant images even at night and at twilight, providing a special viewing pleasure. The comfortable 45 degree viewing angle allows fatigue-free use even when the binoculars are tilted strongly.  </span><br><br><b>A large binocular can also be called a double refractor telescope </b><br><span>One complete lens telescope with the full light gathering power is available per eye. Experience a whole new dimension of observing. Objects are reproduced almost vividly in these binoculars and observing with both eyes is basically very relaxed. Last but not least, this comfortable way of observation increases the recognition of the finest details and effectively prevents rapid eye fatigue. </span><br><br><b>Extremely robust binoculars with magnesium housing, sealed and filled with nitrogen  </b><br><span>The BT series binoculars are designed for tough outdoor use. The IPX6 sealed and nitrogen-filled design effectively prevents fogging of the internal optics even under difficult weather conditions. The very light magnesium housing saves weight and makes it easy to handle. Two EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC 20mm eyepieces of the 62 degree LER series already included. EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC is an established manufacturer of extremely high-quality eyepieces in the astronomy scene. An optical system is only as good as its weakest component. Therefore we have decided to deliver these giant binoculars with a pair of quality eyepieces of the 62 degree LER series. With an apparent field of view of 62 degrees and a focal length of 20mm, the BT-100 binoculars produce a 28x magnification. Thus these wide angle eyepieces offer a very good overview (field of view 2,3 degree) at moderate magnification. The large interpupillary distance of these LER (long eye relief) eyepieces of 15mm and soft silicone eyecups, which can be turned inside out, also guarantee a comfortable and relaxed view. For astronomy, a flat and sharp image field is advantageous and offers a particularly impressive viewing experience even during the day. Due to the waterproof design and the argon filling, these eyepieces are absolutely durable and easy to clean. </span><br><br><b>Interchangeable eyepieces with 1.25 inch / 31.7mm plug-in diameter </b><br><span>Adjust the magnification and field of view to your individual needs and choose from a wide range of available eyepieces. All eyepiece types with a plug-in diameter of 1.25 inch / 31.7mm can be used with the binoculars of the BT series. Especially recommended are EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC eyepieces of the 62 and 82 degree series with focal lengths from 8 to 26mm (see item No. 02188xx and 02196xx). The magnification can be varied from 21x to 70x (focal length binoculars : focal length eyepiece = magnification). The eyepieces are held in the binoculars by a precise brass compression ring clamp and guarantee a tilt free position.  </span><br><br><b>Use of color and nebula filters for astronomical observations </b><br><span>Increase the contrast and visibility of objects and details by screwing the corresponding filters directly into the thread of the eyepiece sleeves. The use of color and nebula filters must of course always be done in pairs. Suitable are all EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC screw filters with 1.25inch / 31.7mm diameter (see item No. 03102xx)  </span><br><br><b>Comfortable 45 degree view and helical single focus </b><br><span>The 45-degree viewing angle allows a relaxed observation position even when the binoculars are tilted strongly. Also the individual interpupillary distance can be adjusted in a range from 54 to 76mm. With the fine helical individual focusing, precise focusing is achieved effortlessly. Extendable dew caps The integrated dew caps can be removed in high humidity and cold conditions. This avoids fogging of the outer objective lenses and effectively shields additional control light coming in from the side. </span><br><br><b>Integrated carrying handle </b><br><span>A metal carrying handle located at the center of gravity facilitates transport and ensures a secure hold during tripod assembly. </span><br><br><b>Suitable tripods and tripod connection<br></b>When using these large binoculars, a sturdy photo tripod with an appropriate load capacity is highly recommended. The connection is made via two 1/4 inch or one 3/8 inch threaded holes (standard photo tripod thread) in the tripod adapter of the binoculars. The ideal solution is to use the optional availlable EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC U-Mount with field tripod (item No. 01-14300). This is specially designed for the large binoculars of the BT series and carries these devices absolutely safely. The excellent mechanism with adjustable friction in both axes allows easy moving and tracking. The binocular position is kept stable depending on the adjusted friction intensity. Vibrations are reduced to a minimum by the massive construction of the U-Mount and the large stainless steel tripod. Even at high magnification there are no vibrations and the finest details can be observed.</p>
<!--end tab--><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="specs">Specs</h1>
<table>
<colgroup> <col> </colgroup>
<thead></thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Item Number</td>
<td>01-14220</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Optical design</td>
<td>Achromatic refractor Porro</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mirror / lens diameter</td>
<td>100 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Focal length</td>
<td>550 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Focal ratio</td>
<td>5.5</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Apparent Facial field</td>
<td>62 degrees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Type of remuneration</td>
<td>Enhanced Multilayer Desposition (EMD)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Exit pupil min.</td>
<td>3.6 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Field of view</td>
<td>2.3 degrees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Waterproof</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Water resistance protection level</td>
<td>IPX6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Exit pupil distance</td>
<td>15 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total length</td>
<td>520 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total width</td>
<td>270 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total height</td>
<td>155 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total net weight</td>
<td>6800 g</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Housing material</td>
<td>Mgnesium</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><!--end tab--><!--start tab--></p>
<h1 id="features">Warranty</h1>
<p>Explore Scientific offers free collimation service for the Giant Binoculars for the lifetime of the product. The customer is responsible for shipping both ways. <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/apps/product-registration" target="_blank">Explore Scientific Giant Binoculars come with a 1-year warranty when registered within 60 days of purchase. </a></p>
<p>The Explore Alliance membership program offers Extended Care for all Explore Scientific products with a paid membership. For more information on the Explore Alliance <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/products/explore-alliance-membership" target="_blank">Click Here</a> </p>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="manual">Manual</h1>
<p><a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0390/6029/files/BT_SF_Large_Binoculars.pdf?v=1625680797">Download Manual Here</a></p>
<p><!--end tab--></p>
<p style="font-size: 16px;" data-mce-style="font-size: 16px;">CA Residents: <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/pages/prop65" target="_blank">Prop 65 WARNING(S)</a></p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>1.1Options:Objective Diameter*70mm~/products/bt-70-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.2Options:Objective Diameter*82mm~/products/bt-82-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.3Options:Objective Diameter*100mm~/products/bt-100-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.4Options:Objective Diameter*120mm~/products/bt-120-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1000-2000</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1800-2000</s:tag>
    <s:tag>binoculars</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Brand_ Explore Scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Astronomy</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Birding</s:tag>
    <s:tag>explore-scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>over-500</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-default</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-disabled</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209308524716</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="USD">1999.99</s:price>
      <s:sku>01-14220</s:sku>
      <s:grams>10000</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209303347372</id>
    <published>2021-01-26T13:55:15-06:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-26T13:55:15-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/bt-82-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces"/>
    <title>BT-82 SF Large Binoculars with 62 Degree LER Eyepieces</title>
    <s:type>Binoculars</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Explore Scientific</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0390/6029/products/5bf0ebefe92d06b607b32dd75d2d09d4_0114210_m_1.jpg?v=1614378476"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Explore Scientific<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Binoculars<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            1799.99
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="features">Features</h1>
<ul>
<li>Powerful large binoculars with a 82 mm objective diameter</li>
<li>Observe the moon, the planets and bright deep sky objects in the night sky as well as terrestrial targets</li>
<li>Extremely robust binoculars, sealed and filled with nitrogen</li>
<li>Convenient 45-degree view and individual focusing</li>
<li>Carrying handle makes it easier to transport the binocular and ensures a secure hold during tripod assembly</li>
<li>Includes two premium waterproof Explore Scientific 62 degree 20mm LER eyepieces</li>
<li>Eyepiece holder 1.25 inch / 31.7mm, interchangeable eyepieces</li>
<li>Extendable dew caps minimize condensation on the lenses</li>
<li>Tripod connection: 2 x 1/4 inch and 1 x 3/8 inch photo thread</li>
<li>Optional accessories: <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/products/u-mount-with-tripod-for-large-binoculars" target="_blank">Item 01-14300 U-mount with field tripod</a>
</li>
</ul>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="description">Description</h1>
<p><meta charset="utf-8"><b>Giant binocular for observing the starry sky, nature and landscape. </b><br><span>Observe the beauty of the starry sky at night and distant objects in nature during the day. Globular star clusters, glowing gas nebulae, the moon with its craters and even planets can be observed wonderfully on a clear night. But also all other distant things in nature and landscape, even ships and airplanes can be seen in detail. With the all-round binoculars of the EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC BT series, you can get up very close. Thanks to the large, light-gathering lenses and the professional coatings on all lens surfaces, these binoculars produce bright and brilliant images even at night and at twilight, providing a special viewing pleasure. The comfortable 45 degree viewing angle allows fatigue-free use even when the binoculars are tilted strongly.  </span><br><br><b>A large binocular can also be called a double refractor telescope </b><br><span>One complete lens telescope with the full light gathering power is available per eye. Experience a whole new dimension of observing. Objects are reproduced almost vividly in these binoculars and observing with both eyes is basically very relaxed. Last but not least, this comfortable way of observation increases the recognition of the finest details and effectively prevents rapid eye fatigue. </span><br><br><b>Extremely robust binoculars with magnesium housing, sealed and filled with nitrogen  </b><br><span>The BT series binoculars are designed for tough outdoor use. The IPX6 sealed and nitrogen-filled design effectively prevents fogging of the internal optics even under difficult weather conditions. The very light magnesium housing saves weight and makes it easy to handle. Two EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC 20mm eyepieces of the 62 degree LER series already included. EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC is an established manufacturer of extremely high-quality eyepieces in the astronomy scene. An optical system is only as good as its weakest component. Therefore we have decided to deliver these giant binoculars with a pair of quality eyepieces of the 62 degree LER series. With an apparent field of view of 62 degrees and a focal length of 20mm, the BT-82 binoculars produce a 24x magnification. Thus these wide-angle eyepieces offer a very good overview (field of view 2,6 degree) at moderate magnification. The large interpupillary distance of these LER (long eye relief) eyepieces of 15mm and soft silicone eyecups, which can be turned inside out, also guarantee a comfortable and relaxed view. For astronomy, a flat and sharp image field is advantageous and offers a particularly impressive viewing experience even during the day. Due to the waterproof design and the argon filling, these eyepieces are absolutely durable and easy to clean. </span><br><br><b>Interchangeable eyepieces with 1.25 inch / 31.7mm plug-in diameter </b><br><span>Adjust the magnification and field of view to your individual needs and choose from a wide range of available eyepieces. All eyepiece types with a plug-in diameter of 1.25 inch / 31.7mm can be used with the binoculars of the BT series. Especially recommended are EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC eyepieces of the 62 and 82 degree series with focal lengths from 8 to 26mm (see item No. 02188xx and 02196xx). The magnification can be varied from 18x to 60x (focal length binoculars: focal length eyepiece = magnification). The eyepieces are held in the binoculars by a precise brass compression ring clamp and guarantee a tilt free position.  </span><br><br><b>Use of color and nebula filters for astronomical observations </b><br><span>Increase the contrast and visibility of objects and details by screwing the corresponding filters directly into the thread of the eyepiece sleeves. The use of color and nebula filters must of course always be done in pairs. Suitable are all EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC screw filters with 1.25inch / 31.7mm diameter (see item No. 03102xx)  </span><br><br><b>Comfortable 45 degree view and helical single focus </b><br><span>The 45-degree viewing angle allows a relaxed observation position even when the binoculars are tilted strongly. Also the individual interpupillary distance can be adjusted in a range from 54 to 76mm. With the fine helical individual focusing, precise focusing is achieved effortlessly. Extendable dew caps The integrated dew caps can be removed in high humidity and cold conditions. This avoids fogging of the outer objective lenses and effectively shields additional control light coming in from the side. </span><br><br><b>Integrated carrying handle </b><br><span>A metal carrying handle located at the center of gravity facilitates transport and ensures a secure hold during tripod assembly. </span><br><br><b>Suitable tripods and tripod connection<br></b>When using these large binoculars, a sturdy photo tripod with an appropriate load capacity is highly recommended. The connection is made via two 1/4 inch or one 3/8 inch threaded holes (standard photo tripod thread) in the tripod adapter of the binoculars. The ideal solution is to use the optional available EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC U-Mount with field tripod (item No. 01-14300). This is specially designed for the large binoculars of the BT series and carries these devices absolutely safely. The excellent mechanism with adjustable friction in both axes allows easy moving and tracking. The binocular position is kept stable depending on the adjusted friction intensity. Vibrations are reduced to a minimum by the massive construction of the U-Mount and the large stainless steel tripod. Even at high magnification there are no vibrations and the finest details can be observed.</p>
<!--end tab--><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="specs">Specs</h1>
<table>
<colgroup> <col> </colgroup>
<thead></thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Item Number</td>
<td>01-14210</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Optical design</td>
<td>Achromatic refractor Porro</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mirror / lens diameter</td>
<td>82 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Focal length</td>
<td>470 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Focal ratio</td>
<td>5.7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Apparent Facial field</td>
<td>62 degrees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Type of remuneration</td>
<td>Enhanced Multilayer Desposition (EMD)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Exit pupil min.</td>
<td>3.5 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Field of view</td>
<td>2.6 degrees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Waterproof</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Water resistance protection level</td>
<td>IPX6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Exit pupil distance</td>
<td>15 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total length</td>
<td>445 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total width</td>
<td>226 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total height</td>
<td>122 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total net weight</td>
<td>4300 g</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Housing material</td>
<td>Mgnesium</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><!--end tab--><!--start tab--></p>
<h1 id="features">Warranty</h1>
<p>Explore Scientific offers free collimation service for the Giant Binoculars for the lifetime of the product. The customer is responsible for shipping both ways. <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/apps/product-registration" target="_blank">Explore Scientific Giant Binoculars come with a 1-year warranty when registered within 60 days of purchase. </a></p>
<p>The Explore Alliance membership program offers Extended Care for all Explore Scientific products with a paid membership. For more information on the Explore Alliance <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/products/explore-alliance-membership" target="_blank">Click Here</a> </p>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="manual">Manual</h1>
<p><a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0390/6029/files/BT_SF_Large_Binoculars.pdf?v=1625680797">Download Manual Here</a></p>
<p><!--end tab--></p>
<p style="font-size: 16px;">CA Residents: <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/pages/prop65" target="_blank">Prop 65 WARNING(S)</a></p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>1.1Options:Objective Diameter*70mm~/products/bt-70-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.2Options:Objective Diameter*82mm~/products/bt-82-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.3Options:Objective Diameter*100mm~/products/bt-100-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.4Options:Objective Diameter*120mm~/products/bt-120-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1000-2000</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1600-1800</s:tag>
    <s:tag>binoculars</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Brand_ Explore Scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Astronomy</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Birding</s:tag>
    <s:tag>explore-scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>over-500</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-default</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-disabled</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209303347372</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="USD">1799.99</s:price>
      <s:sku>01-14210</s:sku>
      <s:grams>6900</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209282310316</id>
    <published>2021-01-26T13:55:06-06:00</published>
    <updated>2021-01-26T13:55:06-06:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/bt-70-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces"/>
    <title>BT-70 SF Large Binoculars with 62 Degree LER Eyepieces</title>
    <s:type>Binoculars</s:type>
    <s:vendor>Explore Scientific</s:vendor>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<table border="0">
  <tr>
    <td width="200"><img width="200" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0390/6029/products/04a2baeb77cfddfe85c76fd897a8c898_0114200_m_1.jpg?v=1611088423"></td>
    <td valign="bottom">
      <p>

        <strong>Vendor: </strong>Explore Scientific<br>
        <strong>Type: </strong>Binoculars<br>
        <strong>Price: </strong>
            1599.99
      </p>
    </td>
  </tr>
  <tr>
    <td colspan="2"><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="features">Features</h1>
<ul>
<li>Powerful large binoculars with a 70 mm objective diameter</li>
<li>Observe the moon, the planets and bright deep sky objects in the night sky as well as terrestrial targets</li>
<li>Extremely robust binoculars, sealed and filled with nitrogen</li>
<li>Convenient 45-degree view and individual focusing</li>
<li>Carrying handle makes it easier to transport the binocular and ensures a secure hold during tripod assembly</li>
<li>Includes two premium waterproof Explore Scientific 62 degree 20mm LER eyepieces</li>
<li>Eyepiece holder 1.25 inch / 31.7mm, interchangeable eyepieces</li>
<li>Extendable dew caps minimize condensation on the lenses</li>
<li>Tripod connection: 2 x 1/4 inch and 1 x 3/8 inch photo thread</li>
<li>Optional accessories: <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/products/u-mount-with-tripod-for-large-binoculars" target="_blank">Item 01-14300 U-mount with field tripod</a>
</li>
</ul>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="description">Description</h1>
<p><meta charset="utf-8"><b>Giant binocular for observing the starry sky, nature and landscape. </b><br><span>Observe the beauty of the starry sky at night and distant objects in nature during the day. Globular star clusters, glowing gas nebulae, the moon with its craters and even planets can be observed wonderfully on a clear night. But also all other distant things in nature and landscape, even ships and airplanes can be seen in detail. With the all-round binoculars of the EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC BT series, you can get up very close. Thanks to the large, light-gathering lenses and the professional coatings on all lens surfaces, these binoculars produce bright and brilliant images even at night and at twilight, providing a special viewing pleasure. The comfortable 45 degree viewing angle allows fatigue-free use even when the binoculars are tilted strongly.  </span><br><br><b>A large binocular can also be called a double refractor telescope </b><br><span>One complete lens telescope with the full light gathering power is available per eye. Experience a whole new dimension of observing. Objects are reproduced almost vividly in these binoculars and observing with both eyes is basically very relaxed. Last but not least, this comfortable way of observation increases the recognition of the finest details and effectively prevents rapid eye fatigue. </span><br><br><b>Extremely robust binoculars with magnesium housing, sealed and filled with nitrogen  </b><br><span>The BT series binoculars are designed for tough outdoor use. The IPX6 sealed and nitrogen-filled design effectively prevents fogging of the internal optics even under difficult weather conditions. The very light magnesium housing saves weight and makes it easy to handle. Two EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC 20mm eyepieces of the 62 degree LER series already included. EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC is an established manufacturer of extremely high-quality eyepieces in the astronomy scene. An optical system is only as good as its weakest component. Therefore we have decided to deliver these giant binoculars with a pair of quality eyepieces of the 62 degree LER series. With an apparent field of view of 62 degrees and a focal length of 20mm, the BT-70 binoculars produce a 20x magnification. Thus these wide angle eyepieces offer a very good overview (field of view 3,1 degree) at moderate magnification. The large interpupillary distance of these LER (long eye relief) eyepieces of 15mm and soft silicone eyecups, which can be turned inside out, also guarantee a comfortable and relaxed view. For astronomy, a flat and sharp image field is advantageous and offers a particularly impressive viewing experience even during the day. Due to the waterproof design and the argon filling, these eyepieces are absolutely durable and easy to clean. </span><br><br><b>Interchangeable eyepieces with 1.25 inch / 31.7mm plug-in diameter </b><br><span>Adjust the magnification and field of view to your individual needs and choose from a wide range of available eyepieces. All eyepiece types with a plug-in diameter of 1.25 inch / 31.7mm can be used with the binoculars of the BT series. Especially recommended are EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC eyepieces of the 62 and 82 degree series with focal lengths from 8 to 26mm (see item No. 02188xx and 02196xx). The magnification can be varied from 15x to 50x (focal length binoculars : focal length eyepiece = magnification). The eyepieces are held in the binoculars by a precise brass compression ring clamp and guarantee a tilt free position.  </span><br><br><b>Use of color and nebula filters for astronomical observations </b><br><span>Increase the contrast and visibility of objects and details by screwing the corresponding filters directly into the thread of the eyepiece sleeves. The use of color and nebula filters must of course always be done in pairs. Suitable are all EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC screw filters with 1.25inch / 31.7mm diameter (see item No. 03102xx)  </span><br><br><b>Comfortable 45 degree view and helical single focus </b><br><span>The 45-degree viewing angle allows a relaxed observation position even when the binoculars are tilted strongly. Also the individual interpupillary distance can be adjusted in a range from 54 to 76mm. With the fine helical individual focusing, precise focusing is achieved effortlessly. Extendable dew caps The integrated dew caps can be removed in high humidity and cold conditions. This avoids fogging of the outer objective lenses and effectively shields additional control light coming in from the side. </span><br><br><b>Integrated carrying handle </b><br><span>A metal carrying handle located at the center of gravity facilitates transport and ensures a secure hold during tripod assembly. </span><br><br><b>Suitable tripods and tripod connection<br></b>When using these large binoculars, a sturdy photo tripod with an appropriate load capacity is highly recommended. The connection is made via two 1/4 inch or one 3/8 inch threaded holes (standard photo tripod thread) in the tripod adapter of the binoculars. The ideal solution is to use the optional availlable EXPLORE SCIENTIFIC U-Mount with field tripod (item No. 01-14300). This is specially designed for the large binoculars of the BT series and carries these devices absolutely safely. The excellent mechanism with adjustable friction in both axes allows easy moving and tracking. The binocular position is kept stable depending on the adjusted friction intensity. Vibrations are reduced to a minimum by the massive construction of the U-Mount and the large stainless steel tripod. Even at high magnification there are no vibrations and the finest details can be observed.</p>
<!--end tab--><!--start tab-->
<h1 id="specs">Specs</h1>
<table>
<colgroup> <col> </colgroup>
<thead></thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Item Number</td>
<td>01-14200</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Optical design</td>
<td>Achromatic refractor Porro</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mirror / lens diameter</td>
<td>70 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Focal length</td>
<td>400 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Focal ratio</td>
<td>5.7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Apparent Facial field</td>
<td>62 degrees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Type of remuneration</td>
<td>Enhanced Multilayer Desposition (EMD)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Exit pupil min.</td>
<td>3.5 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Field of view</td>
<td>3.1 degrees</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Waterproof</td>
<td>Yes</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Water resistance protection level</td>
<td>IPX6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Exit pupil distance</td>
<td>15 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total length</td>
<td>370 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total width</td>
<td>213 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr></tr>
<tr>
<td>Total height</td>
<td>122 mm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Total net weight</td>
<td>3400 g</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Housing material</td>
<td>Mgnesium</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><!--end tab--><!--start tab--></p>
<h1 id="features">Warranty</h1>
<p>Explore Scientific offers free collimation service for the Giant Binoculars for the lifetime of the product. The customer is responsible for shipping both ways. <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/apps/product-registration" target="_blank">Explore Scientific Giant Binoculars come with a 1-year warranty when registered within 60 days of purchase. </a></p>
<p>The Explore Alliance membership program offers Extended Care for all Explore Scientific products with a paid membership. For more information on the Explore Alliance <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/products/explore-alliance-membership" target="_blank">Click Here</a> </p>
<!--end tab--> <!--start tab-->
<h1 id="manual">Manual</h1>
<p><a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0390/6029/files/BT_SF_Large_Binoculars.pdf?v=1625680797">Download Manual Here</a></p>
<p><!--end tab--></p>
<p style="font-size: 16px;">CA Residents: <a href="https://explorescientificusa.com/pages/prop65" target="_blank">Prop 65 WARNING(S)</a></p></td>
  </tr>
</table>
]]>
    </summary>
    <s:tag>1.1Options:Objective Diameter*70mm~/products/bt-70-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.2Options:Objective Diameter*82mm~/products/bt-82-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.3Options:Objective Diameter*100mm~/products/bt-100-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1.4Options:Objective Diameter*120mm~/products/bt-120-sf-large-binoculars-with-62-degree-ler-eyepieces</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1000-2000</s:tag>
    <s:tag>1400-1600</s:tag>
    <s:tag>binoculars</s:tag>
    <s:tag>Brand_ Explore Scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Astronomy</s:tag>
    <s:tag>By Use_Birding</s:tag>
    <s:tag>explore-scientific</s:tag>
    <s:tag>over-500</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-default</s:tag>
    <s:tag>spo-disabled</s:tag>
    <s:variant>
      <id>https://robert-price.myshopify.com/products/6209282310316</id>
      <title>Default Title</title>
      <s:price currency="USD">1599.99</s:price>
      <s:sku>01-14200</s:sku>
      <s:grams>6200</s:grams>
    </s:variant>
  </entry>
</feed>
